Our most powerful and final weapon...
（司馬(しば)未織(みおり)）
うちらの最大にして最後の武器が
The final battle will be at
the Flames of Revolution.
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎(れんたろう)）
最終決戦の場所は“回帰の炎”だ
In order for you to have
お前が本気で―
the time to truly decide whether
this world is worth saving or not,
この世界を救ってもいいと
考えるまでの時間を作るためにも
we need the world to keep existing.
世界を存続させなきゃダメだ
（保脇(やすわき)卓人(たくと)）フッフフフフ…
This will mean the end of Satomi Rentaro.
これで 里見蓮太郎もおしまいだ
フフフフ…
♪～
～♪
#13 The Ones Who Aspired to Be Gods
The Gastrea are projected
to arrive in ten minutes.
ガストレアの到着予定まで 10分や
Why haven't the batteries come yet?!
どうして バッテリーが来ない！
I don't see any Gastrea in my field of view.
（ティナ）目視範囲に
ガストレアの姿がありません
What useful eyesight she has.
（蛭子(ひるこ)影胤(かげたね)）
便利な目をお持ちのようで
No fair, Owl!
（蛭子小比奈(こひな)）フクロウ ズルい
But not all of the civil officers
have powers like that...
（室戸(むろと) 菫(すみれ)）しかし 全民警が
そんな能力を
持っているわけではない
There's no contact from the JASDF, either.
自衛隊からも
なんの連絡もあれへん
If we haven't received them by now,
（薙沢彰磨(なぎさわしょうま)）今 届いてないなら
最後までないと思うしかない
we should assume we
won't receive them at all.
The Gastrea army have
come through the forest.
（ティナ）
ガストレア軍が森を抜けました
They are heading straight here!
まっすぐ こちらに向かってきます
Satomi-kun, at this rate...
（天童(てんどう)木更(きさら)）
里見くん このままじゃ…
Either the enemy comes
at us and we perish...
（片桐(かたぎり)玉樹(たまき)）
敵に突っ込まれて滅びるか
...or we go after the enemy and perish.
（片桐弓月(ゆづき)）それとも
あたしたちが突っ込んで滅びるか
They will arrive in about five minutes.
（ティナ）
およそ あと５分で到達します
All units, advance!
総員 突撃！
Rentaro!
（藍原延珠(あいはらえんじゅ)）蓮太郎！
Look!
あれ！
What... are those lights?
なんだ？ この光は
This is... the Genan Festival?
これは 幻庵祭(げんあんさい)
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
Satomi-san, it is I.
（聖天子(せいてんし)）里見さん 私です
Seitenshi-sama...
聖天子様！
I see... So you did this.
そうか あんたが…
Satomi-san,
（聖天子）里見さん
この ともし火一つ一つは―
each one of these lights is filled
with the hopes of the
citizens of the Tokyo Area,
東京エリア市民の希望　祈り
as well as their prayers,
and their will to live.
そして 生きたいという意志です
I am leaving the future of the
Tokyo Area in your hands.
東京エリアの未来を
あなたに託します
Go...
行きなさい
With the courage to never give up,
no matter what the battle, and to win.
どんな戦いの中でも諦めず
勝つ勇気を持って
Don't worry.
（蓮太郎）安心しろ
Enju.
延珠
I believe people have two faces.
人間には たぶん ２つの顔がある
Light and dark...
光と闇
And this is the light.
これは 光の顔だ
If you can see the prayers and hope
filling each one of these lights...
この光 一つ一つに込められた
祈りと希望が見えるなら
I can see them!
見える
We have to save everyone.
みんなを助けなきゃ
（蓮太郎）うん
The Gastrea are here!
来ます！
ガストレア軍
後方にアルデバラン
And Aldebaran is at the rear!
（アルデバランの雄たけび）
We will now commence operation
"Rapier's Thrust!"
これより オペレーション
レイピア･スラストを開始する！
（銃声）
（アルデバランの雄たけび）
All right. We're moving on to stage two.
（蓮太郎）よし
オペレーションは第２段階へ入る
All units, advance!
総員 突撃に移れ！
Tina!
ティナ！
I will assist with the assault.
（ティナ）突撃 支援します
Let's go!
行くぞ！
（蓮太郎･延珠）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
A giant Gastrea is heading
straight toward us!
（未織）巨大ガストレア
まっすぐ 突っ込んでくる！
（蓮太郎）うっ
くっ
Run, Satomi-kun!
走って 里見くん！
Rentaro!
蓮太郎！
Damn it!
クソッ
（玉樹）うおー！
（弓月）はっ！ たーっ！
フッ
（ガストレアの雄たけび）
（悲鳴）
Tendo Style Martial Arts:
天童式戦闘術
Homura Kasen!
焔火扇(ほむらかせん)
This isn't good...
マズい… うっ
（銃声）
So this is death...
（影胤）これが死 これが戦争
So this is war...
Marvelous!
すばらしい！
（蓮太郎）うっ…
Should you be wasting
time here, Leader Satomi?
（影胤）こんな所で
暇を潰している場合か？
里見リーダー！
Satomi,
（彰磨）里見
（蓮太郎）はっ
go.
行け
Aldebaran is now only 100 meters away!
（未織）アルデバランまで
距離100メートル！
I see it!
（アルデバランの雄たけび）
（蓮太郎）見えた！
Let's go, Enju!
行くぞ 延珠！
We will now eliminate the enemy.
これより 敵を排除する
（延珠）とりゃー！
（雄たけび）
（延珠）はーっ！
This is the—
（蓮太郎）これで…
What?!
な… 何!?
Rentaro!
蓮太郎！
（蓮太郎）てやー！
The EP bomb has been set!
ＥＰ爆弾 セット完了
It'll go off in one minute!
１分後に爆発する
All units, fall back as fast as you can!
全員 速やかに離脱せよ！
Well done.
お疲れさん
Five, four, three, two, one...
（蓮太郎）５ ４ ３ ２ １…
はっ
（電子音）
あ… まさか！
It can't be...
Miori... Did it fail to go off?
未織　不発か？
Ren...taro...
蓮太郎…
I'm sorry, Satomi-chan...
（未織）ごめんな 里見ちゃん
No...
いや
There's still one way.
１つだけ方法がある
Enju...
延珠
（延珠）えっ？
This is goodbye.
（蓮太郎）お別れだ
Huh?
えっ？ あ…
I always...
（蓮太郎）ずっと…
wanted to be a person worthy of you.
お前にふさわしい人間に
なりたいと思ってた
For the year since I met you, I was truly happy.
お前と会って
この１年間 俺は幸せだった
I'm truly thankful
お前と出会えて 本当によかった
that I met you.
Don't g—
行かな…
（殴る音）
If I can apply enough direct force,
the EP bomb should go off...
（蓮太郎）
ヤツに直接 衝撃を与えれば―
ＥＰ爆弾は爆発するはず
Satomi...
（彰磨）里見…
But only
（蓮太郎）ただし…
at point blank range!
ゼロ距離でだ！
Ren...taro...
蓮太郎…
うあー！
うっ… ぐっ
Varanium-corroding fluid!
バラニウム侵食液
N-No!
そ… そんな！
ぐっ… うっ
ううっ… クソッ
Damn it...
Just a little more... and Aldebaran will be...
もう少しで アルデバランを…
うっ
うっ！
No... Not here...
こんな所で…
Satomi, looks like they got you good.
（彰磨）里見 随分やられたな
Shoma-nii...
（蓮太郎）彰磨兄(にい)…
Why?
どうして？
I'm pretty sure I've figured
out what's going on...
状況は把握している
I'll go.
We have to... send an shock
wave deep into its body...
俺が行こう
あいつには 体内深くに…
衝撃を与えないと…
My attack has the ability to destroy
opponents from the inside.
俺の技なら
物体を内部から破壊する力がある
No, Shoma-nii.
ダメだ 彰磨兄…
No! You'll die!
ダメだ！
死んじまう！
My attack is considered heresy...
（彰磨）俺の技は外道の技
I have to seal this attack
deep within the earth.
この技は
金輪際 封印しなきゃならん
Along with Aldebaran...
あのアルデバランと共にな
Satomi...
里見… 俺の分も生きてくれ
Live on for my sake, as well.
Shoma-nii!
彰磨兄！
（彰磨）うあー！
No!
ダメだー！
（延珠）うっ…
Enju...
延珠…
うっ
What is this?
なんだ これは…
Shoma-nii... along with Aldebaran...
彰磨兄 アルデバランと一緒に…
I know... Tina saw everything.
ああ ティナが全部見てたそうだ
What about the remaining Gastrea?
残りのガストレアは？
After Aldebaran exploded,
their movements became strange
アルデバランの爆発と同時に
動きがおかしくなって
and they started to scatter,
so they were easy to defeat.
バラバラの行動を始めたので
倒しやすかった
Most of them escaped outside
of the Monoliths, though.
大半は モノリスの外に
逃げたけどな
Satomi-kun.
（木更）里見くん
Onii-san.
お兄さん
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
Is this... all that's left?
（蓮太郎）こんだけ… なのか？
This is it?
たった こんだけ…
With the destruction of the
Stage Four Gastrea, Aldebaran,
（蓮太郎）第三次関東会戦は―
ステージⅣガストレア
アルデバランの撃滅をもって―
humanity won The Third Kanto Battle.
人間側が勝利した
It has been two days since the
victory of the Kanto Battle,
（アナウンサー）関東会戦勝利から
２日がたちますが―
and it appears that the construction
of the new Monolith 32
新しい32号モノリスの建設は
順調に進んでいるもようです
is progressing as planned.
The height has already surpassed 300 meters,
すでに 高さは
300メートルを超えて―
and it is presumed to be greatly
affecting Gastrea in the area.
周辺にいるガストレアに―
多大な影響を与えていると
推測されます
We have arrived, Kazumitsu-sama.
（椎名(しいな)かずみ）
着きましたわ 和光(かずみつ)様
Welcome, Kazumitsu-oniisama.
ようこそ 和光お兄様
No...
いえ
Should I call you the Vice Minister
国土交通省副大臣様と
お呼びしたほうが
of Land, Infrastructure,
Transport, and Tourism?
よかったでしょうか？
Kisara...
（天童和光）木更…
And I see you have a child, Rentaro.
そっちは子連れか
蓮太郎
Do you have the promised item?
約束のものは？
Damn it! I thought I got rid of all these...
クソッ
全部 処分したはずが！
I had always thought it was strange...
私は ずっと不思議に
思っていました
Why did Aldebaran stick itself to the Monolith?
どうして アルデバランが
モノリスに取りついたのかと
The one who was placing orders for materials
ガストレア大戦末期に建造された
for Monolith 32 towards the
end of the Gastrea War...
32号モノリスの発注を
取りまとめていたのは…
was you, wasn't it?
和光お兄様ですね？
（和光）うっ…
I don't think I can approve of you
（木更）バラニウムに混ぜ物をして
安くモノリスを造って―
mixing other ingredients with the Varanium
so the Monolith could be
made cheaply and you could
浮いた費用を懐に入れるのは
感心しませんね
pocket the rest of the money.
Logically, that purity should have been fine!
理論上は あの純度でも
大丈夫だったんだ！
But it didn't work on Aldebaran.
でも アルデバランには
通用しなかった
（和光）うっ
And with the money you appropriated,
そうして 手に入れたお金で
あなたは 今の地位を手に入れた
you were able to achieve
your current status.
The one who pulled the trigger
on the Third Kanto Battle is you.
第三次関東会戦の引き金を
引いたのは あなたです
You're one of the pieces of
human trash that should have
あなたのような 人間のクズこそが
ガストレア大戦で死ぬべきだった
died in the battle with the Gastrea!
ハハハハ…
A true villain doesn't perish!
真の悪人は死なない！
I can throw money around,
カネをばらまいて
and while "death" is picking that up, I can flee!
死がそれを拾い集めている間に
逃げおおせる！
Both parties, bring forth a witness.
双方 立会人を前に
I, Shiina Kazumi,
（かずみ）私(わたくし) 椎名かずみは
am here to witness this duel.
この場の決闘の
立会人として存在し―
I swear that, even if either
participant in this duel is killed,
たとえ この場で
片方が殺されようとも―
I will not go to the police or any
other administration of the law.
警察 その他の司法機関には
訴え出ないことを ここに誓います
Do you two really have to go
through with this duel?
２人とも
この戦い どうしても
やんなきゃダメなのか？
Rentaro, I must forever silence this
wench's mouth right here and now.
蓮太郎
ここで この女の口を
封じておかなければならんのだ
Satomi-kun, I've been waiting ten years for this.
（木更）里見くん
私は 10年待ったわ
I've finally tracked down one
of the people responsible
お父様とお母様の敵(かたき)の１人
for my mother and father's deaths.
ようやく 追い詰めたの
My battle with him is my destiny.
この男との戦いは 宿命だったのよ
Damn it...
（蓮太郎）チクショウ…
Tendo Martial Arts Divine Spear
practitioner, Tendo Kazumitsu.
天童式神槍(しんそう)術 皆伝
天童和光
Tendo Martial Arts Sword Drawing
practitioner, Tendo Kisara.
天童式抜刀術 皆伝
天童木更
（和光）ぬん！
あっ
What is that style?!
なんだ その型は
Tendo Martial Arts Sword Drawing,
Ryukosogeki stance.
（木更）
天童式抜刀術 龍虎双撃(りゅうこそうげき)の構え
It is the style that I created to
全ての天童を葬るために
私が編み出した型です
destroy every member of the Tendo family.
Enough nonsense!
ふざけるな！
Amako Genmeika!
天子玄明窩(あまこげんめいか)！
（和光）あ…
（木更）はっ
（和光）うわー！
Tendo Martial Arts Sword
Drawing Zero Style, Number 3:
（木更）天童式抜刀術 零(ぜろ)の型三番
Agiosotoken.
阿魏悪双頭剣(あぎおそうとうけん)
That is the name of the move
I used to strike you, Onii-sama.
これが お兄様を斬った技の
名前です
Z-Zero Style?
（和光）ぜ… 零の型だと？
It is one strike, yet two.
１撃をして２撃
The second strike is faster
than the speed of sound.
２撃目の速さは音速を超えます
You couldn't see the second strike
that severed your left leg, Onii-sama.
お兄様には
自分の左足を斬った２撃目が
見えなかったのです
Now, Onii-sama, talk.
さあ お兄様 しゃべってください
About the attack ten years ago
in which my parents were killed.
10年前 私の両親が殺された
襲撃事件のことを
Do you think that stray Gastrea appearing
東京エリアの中心部に
in the heart of the Tokyo Area is plausible?
野良ガストレアが出るなんてこと
ありえると思いますか？
I don't know!
（和光）知らない
Th-There were a total of five
who were involved in the plan.
うっ！
け… 計画に携わっていたのは５人
Myself, three of my brothers,
and Tendo Kikunojo.
私と兄弟３人
そして 天童菊之丞(きくのじょう)
Why did you do such a thing?
（木更）お兄様たちは
なぜ そんなことを？
Father was going to expose the
darkness of the Tendo clan.
親父(おやじ)殿は 天童の闇を
告発しようとしていた
Darkness?
（木更）闇？
Everything like what just happened!
今のようなことを全てだ
For the Tendo clan to obtain its current status,
天童家が今の地位を築くには
many similar incidents have happened over time.
似たようなことが
多々 存在しているのだ
But then, Father suddenly decided
he was going to go public with it...
それを親父殿は突然
表沙汰にしようとして…
So we planned to eliminate him,
along with the rest of you...
それで お前たちも一緒にと…
I see...
そうですか
A-Are you going to spare me?
（和光）た… 助けてくれるのか？
Satomi-kun, Enju-chan, Tina-chan, let's go.
（木更）里見くん 延珠ちゃん
ティナちゃん 行きましょう
（和光）ああ… うっ
（かずみ）ああっ！
Thank you! Thank you!
ありがとう ありがとう
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
（和光）ありがとう
ありがとう ありがとう…
Satomi-kun, he's annoying,
so could you shut the door?
（木更）里見くん
うるさいから
戸を引いてちょうだい
Right...
（蓮太郎）ああ
Kisara-san, is this really...
木更さん これで本当に…
It is one strike, yet two.
（木更）１撃をして２撃
Satomi-kun,
里見くん
２撃目は足だけじゃないの
the second strike didn't just take his leg...
Huh?
えっ？
（和光）ああ… うわー！
（かずみ）うわー！
はっ！
（かずみ）あ…
くっ
Rentaro?
（延珠）蓮太郎？
What was that?
（ティナ）今のは？
Don't look!
（蓮太郎）見るな
（ティナ･延珠）あっ
（延珠）あ…
Satomi-kun, I did it!
里見くん
私 やったわよ
I finally killed one of the people
responsible for my parents' deaths!
やっと お父様たちの敵の１人を
殺したの！
Isn't that amazing?
すごいでしょ！
Is something the matter?
どうかしたの？
里見くんは うれしくないの？
Aren't you happy, Satomi-kun?
This is our revenge!
これは 私たちの復讐(ふくしゅう)じゃない
It was your execution!
あんたの処刑だろ！
Why did you kill Kazumitsu-niisan?
どうして 和光兄さんを殺した？
You knew before you did it, didn't you?
あんた やる前から
分かってたんだろ！
Where is there justice in that?!
木更さん
あれのどこに正義があるんだ！
Satomi-kun, I've realized something.
（木更）里見くん
私 気づいちゃったの
You weren't able to slay Tendo Kikunojo,
里見くんは 影胤事件の黒幕
天童菊之丞も
who was behind the Kagetane
incident, or Saitake Sogen,
狙撃事件の斉武宗玄(さいたけそうげん)も
裁くことができなかった
who was behind the sniping incident.
But I was able to slay Tendo Kazumitsu.
でも 私は
天童和光を裁くことができた
Do you know why?
どうしてだか分かる？
Because I am "evil."
それは 私が“悪”だからよ
Your fists of justice
里見くんの正義の拳は
悪には届かない
can never touch evil.
It is not justice that can oppose evil.
悪に対抗できるのは 正義じゃない
It is an absolute evil that
overpowers evil itself.
悪を上回る“絶対悪”なの
I have that power... I just confirmed it!
私には その力がある
今 確信したわ
Tina... Enju...
（蓮太郎）ティナ 延珠…
I might end up as Kisara-san's enemy...
俺は 木更さんの
敵になるかもしれない
Now that we have overcome
this national crisis,
（聖天子）
この国難を乗り切った我々に―
we have been given another
chance at harmony.
再び 融和の機会が訪れたのです
I believe that establishing
the New Gastrea Law
ガストレア新法を
成立させることが―
will let many of the souls who
died in this battle finally rest.
この戦いで亡くなった―
多くの人々への
鎮魂になると信じます
Currently, we are having girls,
who are all very young,
私(わたくし)たちは今―
本来なら 年端もいかぬ子供である
少女たちに―
bear too heavy a burden.
あまりにも多くのものを
背負わせています
At this time, there may not
be any other choice...
今は それ以外に―
選択肢が
ないのかもしれません
However, in the future,
しかし―
there may come a day when
their burden can be lifted.
未来には いつか彼女たちが
荷を下ろせる日が来るはず
No, it is us who will make that day a reality!
いえ 私たちが きっと―
その日を作るのです！
（人々の歓声）
Ceremony of conferment of decoration?
（延珠）叙勲式？
Yeah. At the Sacred Palace
where Seitenshi-sama lives.
（蓮太郎）ああ
聖天子様の住んでいる聖居でな
Apparently they're going to congratulate us.
俺たちを祝ってくれるんだとさ
Is this attire appropriate?
いいのか？ この格好で
It's fine.
いいんだ
I see...
そっか
Oh, that's right!
そうだ！
Here. This is for you, Rentaro.
蓮太郎に これ！
（蓮太郎）ん？
An oath?
“誓約書”？
"One: You will not face an enemy alone.
“１　１人で
敵に向かっていったりしない”
Two: We will do everything together.
“２　なんでも２人でする”
Three: Don't knock me
unconscious without warning"...
“３　黙って妾(わらわ)を
気絶させたりしない”
Yes!
（延珠）うん！
"Four"...
“４…”
（電車のブレーキ音）
おっ
A fatal accident has occurred
at the Third District Station.
（アナウンス）
第３区駅構内にて―
人身事故が発生しました
We request your patience.
しばらく お待ちください
ハァ…
Now we're going to be late...
こりゃ 遅刻だな
I wonder if it hurt...
痛かったかな？
I wonder if it was painful...
つらかったのかな？
Was there nothing that we could have done?
妾たちが
何かしてあげられることって―
なかったのかな？
あ… なあ 蓮太郎
Hey, Rentaro?
（蓮太郎）うっ…
あ… どうしたのだ？ 蓮太郎
What is the matter, Rentaro?
I'm afraid I'm becoming
（蓮太郎）他人の死に―
unaffected by the deaths of others...
マヒしていく自分が
怖いんだ
Enju... Please stay by my side, always...
延珠
ずっと そばにいてくれ
Don't let me go.
俺を離さないでくれ
It's all right, Rentaro.
大丈夫だ 蓮太郎
You and I will always be
together, forever and ever.
妾と蓮太郎だけは
ずっと ずっと 一緒だから